<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science on Elias Forsblom</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/tags/data-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science on Elias Forsblom</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/tags/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>financeR</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/posts/2021-01-24-financer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/posts/2021-01-24-financer/</guid>
      <description>financeR, a R wrapper which makes it easier to access and download stock data in bulk&#xA;It’s been quite some time since I posted on this blog now, and the reason for that is - except for a lot of school - that I spent almost all my spare time developing an R package which ended up being quite time consuming and a lot bigger than I first expected. The package, or wrapper, I developed is called financeR and is something I developed to make it easier to - hint: the name - download and conduct analysis on large amount of stock data using the Financial Modelling Prep API.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Have covid-19 had an effect on how happy or sad music we choose to listen to?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/posts/2020-12-02-covid-19-effect-on-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/posts/2020-12-02-covid-19-effect-on-music/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by the incredible post &amp;ldquo;Using Data to Find the Angriest Death Grips Song&amp;rdquo; by Evan Oppenheimer (Link in the end of this post) I decided I also would play around and get acquainted with the spotify API and at the same time get to better my skills in data science overall.&#xA;Going into this &amp;ldquo;project&amp;rdquo;, and even by the time of starting to write this post I had no idea of what I actually wanted to do, so the first thing I did was to explore the spotify API to see what options i had and if there was someting that I would find intereseting to dig deeper into.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
